Simon, Fanny Records 5169
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Fanny Simon Records
1897-1971
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Simon, S. Fanny, 1903-1989
5169
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Records (documents).
8209405
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 18, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 07, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Fanny Simon was born in 1903 and came to the U.S. from Warsaw just before the outbreak of World War I. A lifelong socialist - she was attracted to the socialists and Eugene Debs for their steadfast opposition to the "capitalists' war" - she joined the Socialist Party in 1929.
She was a brillian student and won a scholarship to Cornell and later went on to Columbia where she received a doctorate in economics. In 1940 she co-authored a book titled 'The American Labor Movement'.
Fanny Simon was a fixture around the United Federation of Teachers well into her 80s, she was one of the founding mothers of Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) and the UFT's Women's Rights Committee, and even found time to work with the labor movement in Mexico.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5169 mf: Fanny Simon Records on Microfilm
Simon, S. Fanny, 1903-1989
8209405
- Integracion Social en Guatemala, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Spanish
  - Item 1: Integracion Social en Guatemala, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    By Eminario de Integracion Social Guatemalteca. Item is in English.
- Cultura Indigena de Guatemala Ensayos de Antropologia Social, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Cultura Indigena de Guatemala, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    By Eminario de Integracion Social Guatemalteca. Ensayos de Antropologia Social. Item is in English.
- Encuesta Sobre La Cultura de Los Ladinos en Guatemala, 1956; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Encuesta Sobre la Cultura de Los Ladinos en Guatemala, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Richard N. Adams. Item is in English.
- The Seat of the Commercial Association of Bahia, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: A Jewel of Colonial Art, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By The Seat of Commercial Association of Bahia. Item is in English.
- Desperta Brasil!, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Desperta Brasil!, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By A Temorio d'Albuquerque. Item is in English.
- Economia de Guatemala, 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Economia de Guatemala, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By Eminario de Integracion Social Guatemalteca. Item is in Spanish.
- Cuadernos del Seminario de Integracion Social Guatemalteca, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Cuadernos del Seminario de Integracion Social Guatemalteca, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    By Joaquin Noval. Cuadernos 1-6. Item is in Spanish.
- Aprismo Cubano APRA, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Teoria y Tactica Aprista, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    By Victor Raul Maya de la Torre. Item is in Spanish.
- Pagina de Quito, 1939; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Paginas de Quito, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Augusto Arias. Item is in Spanish.
- Provincia de Cordoba Ministerio de Gabrieno, 1939; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Leyes, Decretos y Resoluciones Vigentes en Materia Industrial, Obrera y de Prevision Social, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Ministerio de Gobierno Ley Organica del Departamento Provincial del Trabajo. Item is in Spanish.
- Socialismo, Trabajo, y Despilfarro, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: El Pequeno Libro Socialista, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    By Numeros. Item is in Spanish.
- Synthesis of the Colombian Economy, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Synthesis of the Colombian Economy, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    By Luis-Angel Arango. Item is in English.
- Estatuto Buenos Aires 1933, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Cooperativa Limitada de Propietarios de Automoviles de Alquiler y Afines, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    By Federacion Grafica Bonaerense Independencia 1582. Item is in Spanish.
- El Socialismo y las Juventudes, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: El Socialismo y la Juventudes, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    By Congreso de Juventudes des PSE. Item is in Spanish.
- Zonas Agropecuarias de la Provincia de Sante Fe, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Zonas Agropecuarias de la Provincia de Santa Fe, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    By Direccion General de Estadistica de La Provincia de Santa Fe. Item is in Spanish.
- El Popol-Uuh Biblia de Los Maya Quiche, 1923; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: El Popol-Vuh! O Libro Sagrado de Los Antiguos Votanides, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    By Santiago I. Barberena. Item is in Spanish.
- Tiempo y Ritmo de la Aventura, 1940; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Tiempo y Ritmo de la Aventura, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    By Jaime Barrera B. Item is in Spanish.
- El Escuadron de Hierro 1938, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: El Escuadron de Hierro, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
    By Elias Barrios. Item is in Spanish.
- Un Estudio del Costo de la Vida, 1935; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Un Estudio del Costo de la Vida, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    By Federico Bach. Item is in Spanish.
- Revista del Banco de la Republica May 1954 June 1958, 1954-1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: Revista del Banco de la Republica, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    By Banco de la Republica. Item is in Spanish.
- Banco de la Republica XXXIV Informe Annual, 1956-1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: XXXIV Informe Annual del Gerente a la Junta Directiva, Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
    By Banco de la Republica. 2 copies. Item is in English.
- El Fascismo por Dentro 3, Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: El Fascismo por Dentro, Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
    By L Bertone, A. Garofalo, A. G. Garrone. Prensa, escuela y radio bajo Mussolini. Item is in Spanish.
- El Ejercito Revolucionario PNR, 1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: El Ejercito Revolucionario PNR, Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
    By Ignacio M. Beteta. Item is in Spanish.
- La Mendicidad en Mexico beneficencia publica, 1931; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: La Mendicidad en Mexico, Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
    By Beneficendia publica del d. f. Item is in Spanish.
- The Birthplace of the Liberator Simon Bolivar, Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Item 1: The Birthplace of the Liberator Simon Bolivar, Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Item is in English.
- Boletim Sindicalistia de Brasil, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Item 1: Boletim Sindicalista do Brasil, Publication (Box 1, Folder 26)
    By FSBP. three issues. Item is in Portugese.
- Gilberto Bosques Mensaje del P.N.R., 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Item 1: Mensaje del PNR Al Congreso de la Lear, Publication (Box 1, Folder 27)
    By Partido Nacional Revolucionario. Item is in Spanish.
- The National Revolutionary Party of Mexico and the Six-Year Plan, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Item 1: The National Revolutionary Party of Mexico and the Six-Year Plan, Publication (Box 1, Folder 28)
    By Gilberto Bosques. Item is in Spanish.
- O Poder Judiciano no Estado Novo 1939, Publication (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Item 1: O Poder Judiciario no Estado Novo, Publication (Box 1, Folder 29)
    By DNP. Item is in Spanish.
- O Regime e o Exercito 1938, Publication (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Item 1: O Regime e o Exercito, Publication (Box 1, Folder 30)
    By Edificio do Ministerio da Guerra. Item is in Portugese.
- Seguranca Nacional, Publication (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Item 1: Seguranca Nacional, Publication (Box 1, Folder 31)
    By Imprensa Nacional. Item is in Portuguese.
- O Brasil de Hoje, de ontem e de amanha, 1940; Publication (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Item 1: O Brasil de Hoje, de ontem e de amanha, Publication (Box 1, Folder 32)
    By Departmento de Impresna e Propaganda. Item is in Portuguese.
- Enquadramento Sindical Brasileiro, Publication (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Item 1: Enquadramento Sindical Brasileiro, Publication (Box 1, Folder 33)
    By FSBP. Item is in Portuguese.
- Decreto- Lei N. 1402, 1939; Publication (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Item 1: Decreto-Lei N. 1.402, Publication (Box 1, Folder 34)
    By Servico de Estatistica da Previdencia e Trabalho. Item is in Portuguese.
- Reforma de lei de Sindicalizacao, 1939; Publication (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Item 1: Reforma da Lei de Sindicalizacao, Publication (Box 1, Folder 35)
    By Departamento Nacional do Trabalho. Item is in Portuguese.
- Departmento de Assistencia ao cooperativismo, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Item 1: Departamento de Assistencia ao Cooperativismo, Publication (Box 1, Folder 36)
    By Secretaria de Estado dos Negocios da Agricultura, Industria, e Commercio do Estado de S. Paulo. Item is in Portuguese.
- Secretaria de Estado dos Negocros da Educadao, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Item 1: ATO N. 38, Publication (Box 1, Folder 37)
    By Servico de Legislacao e Publicidade da Secretaria da Educacao. Item is in Portuguese.
- Le Bresil - Caracteristiques, Rio de Janiero 1937, Publication (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Item 1: Le Bresil: Caracteristiques, Geographiques, Economiques, Historiques, Sociales, Politiques et Intellectuelles, Publication (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Item is in Portuguese.
  - Item 2: Banco Interamerico de Desarrollo: Sus Antecedentes y Creacion, Publication (Box 1, Folder 38)
    By Julio Broide. Item is in Spanish.
- Banco Interamericano de Desarrollo, Publication (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Consideraciones sobre la Libertad, 1938; Publication (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Item 1: Conferencias, Publication (Box 1, Folder 40)
    By Jose Rafael Bustamante. Item is in Spanish.
- Realidades Ecuatorianas 1938, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Realidades Ecuatorianas, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
    By Curso de Extension Cultural. Item is in Spanish.
- Socialismo y Humanismo, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Socialismo y Humanismo, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
    By Ernestan. El Hombre como Artifice de su Destino. Item is in Spanish.
- Estadistica - Numero 49 November 30, 1952, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1952, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Bibliografia Comentada sobre Antropologia Social 1900-1955, Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Bibliografia Comentada Sobre Antropologia Social, Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
    By Robert H. Ewald. Seminario de Integracion Social Guatemalteca. Item is in Spanish.
- Arbitramento del Rio Magdalena 1946, Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Arbitramento del Rio Magdalena, Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Item is in Spanish.
- Recuperacao do Nordeste 1951, Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Recuperacao do Nordests, Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
    By J Colombo de Sousa, Professor E. Advogado. Item is in Portuguese.
- Tamandre - Joracy Camargo 1939, Publication (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Tamandare, Publication (Box 2, Folder 7)
    By Joracy Camargo. Item is in Portuguese.
- Quick Columbia Facts 1956, Publication (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Quick Colombian Facts, Publication (Box 2, Folder 8)
    By Ernesto Camacho-Leyva. Item is in English.
- Cronzica Moralizada 1939, Publication (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Cronica Moralizada, Publication (Box 2, Folder 9)
    By Fray Antonio de la Calancha. Item is in Spanish.
- Ley del Instituto Nacional de Prevision, 1937; Publication (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Ley del Instituto Nacional de Prevision y de las Cajas de Prevision, Publication (Box 2, Folder 10)
    By FSBP Ecuador. Item is in Spanish.
- El aprismo frente ala VIII Conferencia Panamencana, 1938; Publication (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: El Aprismo Frente a la VII Conferencia Panamericana, Publication (Box 2, Folder 11)
    By Comite Aprista de Mexico. Meixco. Item is in Spanish.
- El Ejido en la Comarca Lagunera 1936, Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: El Ejido en la Comarca Lagunera, Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
    By Lazaro Cardenas. El Siglo de Torreon. Item is in Spanish.
- La Universidad de la Republica en 1959, Publication (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: La Universidad de la Republica en 1959, Publication (Box 2, Folder 13)
    By Mario A. Cassinoni. Item is in Spanish.
- Informe official del tercer Congreso de la Confederacion obrera Pan-Americana, 1921; Publication (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Informe Oficial del Tercer Congreso, Publication (Box 2, Folder 14)
    By Informe Oficial del Tercer Congreso. Item is in Spanish.
- Las Ligas Femenlies de Lucha Social en Los Ejidos, 1937; Publication (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Las Ligas Femeniles de Lucha Social en Los Ejidos, Publication (Box 2, Folder 15)
    By Lazaro Cardenas. Item is in Spanish.
- Lazaro Cardenas A Message to the Mexican Nation 1937, Publication (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: A Message to the Mexican Nation on the Solution of the Agrarian Problem of La Laguna, Publication (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Lazaro Cardenas - Messages to the Mexican Nation on the Oil Question 1938, Publication (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Messages to the Mexican Nation on the Oil Question, Publication (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Lazaros Cardenas New Year's Message 1938, Publication (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: New Year's Message, 1938, Publication (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Resolucion del Problema Agrario de la Comarca Lagunera, 1936; Publication (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Resolucion del Problema Agrario de la Comarca Lagunera, Publication (Box 2, Folder 19)
    By Genil Lazaro Cardenas. Item is in Spanish.
- Lopez Contreras y Medina Angarita, Publication (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: Lopez Contreras y Medina Angarita, Publication (Box 2, Folder 20)
    By Gonzalo Carnevali. Item is in Spanish.
- Es cierto, Publication (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Es Cierto, Publication (Box 2, Folder 21)
- El peru bajo el oprobio 1938, Publication (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: El Peru Bajo El Oprobio, Publication (Box 2, Folder 22)
    By Comite Aprista de Mexico. Item is in Spanish.
- El Obraje embrion de la fabrica, 1938; Publication (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: El Obraje Embrion de la Fabrica, Publication (Box 2, Folder 23)
    By Luis Chaves Orozco. Item is in Spanish.
- Boletin de esadistica 1939, Publication (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: Boletin de Estadistica, Publication (Box 2, Folder 24)
    By Municipalidad Chile. Item is in Spanish.
- Il congreso Nacional, Publication (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Item 1: Resoluciones del II Congreso Nacional de la C. T. Ch., Publication (Box 2, Folder 25)
    By Confederacion de Tabajadores de Chile. Item is in Spanish.
- Confederacion de Trabajadores de Mexico- Estatutos - 1936, Publication (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Item 1: Estatutos, Publication (Box 2, Folder 26)
    By Confederacion de Trabajadores de Mexico. Item is in Spanish.
- El Problema de la Laguna Antechamber Soluciones 1937, Publication (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Item 1: El Problema de la Laguna - Antecedentes, Solucions, Publication (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Resoluciones y Otros Documentos 1950, Publication (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Item 1: Resoluciones y Otros Documentos, Publication (Box 2, Folder 28)
    By Conferencia Interamericana Pro Democracio y Libertad. Item is in Spanish.
- Compania del Ferrocarril Mexicano, 1923; Publication (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Item 1: Compania de Ferrocarril Mexicano, Publication (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Contrato de Trabajo, 1930; Publication (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Item 1: Contrato de Trabajo, Publication (Box 2, Folder 30)
    By Compania Terminal de Veracruz, S.A. Item is in Spanish.
- Compania Agricola de Guatemala United Fruit Company, 1957; Publication (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Item 1: Compania Agricola de Guatemala - United Fruit Company - Datos 1957, Publication (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Actas Finales de los Tres Primeros Congresos 1959, Publication (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Item 1: Actas Finales de los Tres Primeros Congresos Indigenistas Interamericanos, Publication (Box 2, Folder 32)
    By Comite Organizador del IV Congreso Indigenista Interamericano. Curdad de Guatemala. Item is in Spanish.
- Beneficios del Seguro de Vejez y Muerte, 1957; Publication (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Item 1: Beneficios del Seguro de Invalidez, Vejez y Muerte, Publication (Box 2, Folder 33)
    By Costa Rica. Caja Costarricense de Seguno Social. 2 copies. Item is in Spanish.
- The Pullman Company, 1929; Publication (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Item 1: Contrato de Trabajo Celebrado Entre The Pullman Company y la Alianza de Ferrocarrileros Mexicanos, Publication (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Crisol Ano III Tomos VI, Publication (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Item 1: Crisol, Publication (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Crisol Revistadecritica, 1934; Publication (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Item 1: Crisol: Revista de Critica, Publication (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Cuadernos de Manana, 1964; Publication (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Item 1: Cuadernos de Manana No. 4, Publication (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Informe Economico 1955, Publication (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Item 1: Informe Economico, Publication (Box 2, Folder 38)
    By Confederation General Economica de la Republica Argentina. Item is in Spanish.
- C.G.O.C.M. Por La Revolucion Social, 1934; Publication (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Item 1: Estatuto, Publication (Box 2, Folder 39)
    By Confederacioni General de Obreros y Campesinos de Mexico. 2 copies. Item is in Spanish.
- Informe del Consejo Nacional 1933-1934, Publication (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Item 1: Informe del Consejo Nacional, Publication (Box 2, Folder 40)
    By Confederacion General de Obreros y Campesinos de Mexico. Item is in Spanish.
- Caja Costarriense de Seguro Social 1954-1955, Publication (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Item 1: El Hermoso y Efficiente Edificio del Dispensario de Heredia, Publication (Box 2, Folder 41)
    By Caja Costarricense de Seguro Social. Item is in Spanish.
- Planta Hidroelectrica "La Garita" Guia Discriptiva, 1958; Publication (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Item 1: Planta Hidroelectrica 'La Garita' - Guia Descriptiva, Publication (Box 2, Folder 42)
    By Costa Rica. Instituto Costarricense de Electricidad. Item is in Spanish.
- Dinamica economica del Aprismo, Publication (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Item 1: Dinamica Economica del Aprismo, Publication (Box 2, Folder 43)
    By Charles Manuel Cox. Item is in Spanish.
- Mexico- Soviet por Julio Cuadros Caldas 1926, Publication (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Item 1: Mexico-Soviet, Publication (Box 2, Folder 44)
    By Julio Cuadros Caldas. Item is in Spanish.
- Socialismo Utopico Cientifico 1953, Publication (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Item 1: Socialism, Publication (Box 2, Folder 45)
    By Enrique Dickmann. Item is in Spanish.
- Pensamiento y Accion de Emilio Frugoni, Publication (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Item 1: Pensamiento y Accion de Emilio Frugoni, Publication (Box 2, Folder 46)
    By Ricardo Duran Cano. Item is in Spanish.
- Carta del Liberacion, Publication (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Item 1: Carta del Liberacion, No. 2, Publication (Box 2, Folder 47)
    By Daniel Oduber. Item is in Spanish.
- Carta a un Canero, Publication (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Item 1: Carta un Canero - Carta del Liberacion, No. 3, Publication (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Tela Railroad Company 1957, Publication (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Item 1: Datos de la Tela Railroad Company Ano 1957, Publication (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Doctrina Agaista 1930, Publication (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Item 1: Doctrina Agrarista, Publication (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Vientidos Meses de Travion 1941, Publication (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Item 1: 22 Meses de Traicion, Publication (Box 2, Folder 51)
    By Victor Dotti. Item is in Spanish.
- Hacia Donde Vamos?, 1955; Publication (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Item 1: Hacia Donde Vamos, Publication (Box 2, Folder 52)
    By Simon Dubnov. Item is in Spanish.
- Ideas E Ideales 1920, Publication (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Item 1: Ideas e Ideales, Publication (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Marx y Bakunin 1922, Publication (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Item 1: Marx y Bakunin, Publication (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Estatutos del Instituto Nacionel de Prevision, 1937; Publication (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Mensaje de la Biblioteca Nacional, Publication (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Boletin de informacciones y de estudios sociales y Economicos No. 7, No. 9, 1939; Publication (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Caja del Seguro, 1937; Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Em torno de un novo Conceito de Tropicalismo, 1952; Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Em Torno de Um Novo Conceito de Tropicalismo, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    By Conferencia Pronunciada Na Sala Dos Capelos da Universidade de Coimbra. Item is in Portuguese.
- Mensaje a la Juventud, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Mensaje a la Juventud, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    By Publicaciones del Partido Socialista. Item is in Spanish.
- Preceptos Historiales 1957, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Preceptos Historiales, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
    By Editorial del Ministerio de Educacion Publica. Publicaciones del Instituto de Antropologia e Historia de Guatemala. Item is in Spanish.
- O Presidente Geuilo Vargas, 1939; Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: O Presidente Getulio Vargas, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
    By Marcondes Filho. Item is in Portuguese.
- Cartas A Un Cuidadano, 1956; Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Cartas a un Ciudadano, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
    By Jose Figures, Presidente de la Republica. Item is in Spanish.
- Informe Del Ministro De Prevision Social, 1938-1940; Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Genesis, Esencia y Fundamentos del Socialism, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
    By Emilio Frugoni. Item is in Spanish.
- Hacia La Unidad de las Izquierdas Bolivianas, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: El Indio Ecuatoriano, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    By Pio Jaramillo Alvarado. Item is in Spanish.
- El Indio Ecuatoriano, 1936; Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: San Luis Jilotepeque, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
    By John Gillin. Item is in Spanish.
- El Indio Ecuatoriano, 1936; Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: San Luis Jilotepeque, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Genesis Esencia Y Fundamenos Del Socialismo, 1949; Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Elogio a la Constitucion Nacional, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
    By Josue H. Gollan. Item is in Spanish.
- San Luis Jilotepeque, 1958; Publication (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Principios y Defensa de la Democracia, Publication (Box 3, Folder 14)
    By Josue Gollan. Item is in Spanish.
- Spanish Booklets Misc., 1943; Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Juventud Izquierdista de Mexico, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    By Manuel Gonzalez Calzada. Item is in Spanish.
- Spanish Booklets Folder 2, 1932; Publication (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Marx y la Rusia, Publication (Box 3, Folder 16)
    By Julian Gorkin. Item is in Spanish.
  - Item 2: Palabras Gastadas, Publication (Box 3, Folder 16)
    By Jose Figueres. Item is in Spanish.
- Spanish Booklets Folder 3, 1957; Publication (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Problemas de la Economia del Transporte, Publication (Box 3, Folder 17)
    By Antonio Garcia. Item is in Spanish.
  - Item 2: La Ingerencia Rusa en Mexico y Sudamerica, Publication (Box 3, Folder 17)
    By Rodrigo Garcia Trevino. pruebas y testimonios. Item is in Spanish.